<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FAQ on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/</link><description>Recent content in FAQ on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>General Questions &amp; Info</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/about-the-course/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/about-the-course/</guid><description>General description This course is open to any graduate (or advanced undergraduate) at the University of Chicago. We draw from a wide range of departments such as Information Science, Sociology, Psychology, Political Science, etc. Typically these students are looking to learn basic computational and analytic skills they can apply to master’s projects or dissertation research.
If you have never programmed before or don’t know what the shell is, prepare for a different way of approaching problems.</description></item><item><title>Homework Rubric</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/homework-evaluations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/homework-evaluations/</guid><description>Evaluation philosophy The university requires that I assign each student a letter grade at the end of the quarter. However I find that numeric scores on assignments tend to cause students grading anxiety if they do not achieve a perfect 100%. Nor does the numeric score convey specific feedback as to what the student has done well on an assignment, combined with feedback on areas for improvement.
As such, I do not assign numeric scores in this class.</description></item><item><title>How to ask for help</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/asking-questions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/asking-questions/</guid><description>Asking questions is an important part of this class. Remember the 15 minute rule: Once you’ve spent 15 minutes attempting to troubleshoot a problem, ask for help.
Questions should be posted to Ed Discussion in the appropriate category (general v discussion). Here are some tips you should always follow when posting questions.
Introduce the problem with an informative title Bad title: “I need help!” Good title: “Getting a ‘file not found error’ when importing scotus.</description></item></channel></rss>