<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Git?</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/what-is-git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/what-is-git/</guid><description>Why Git? In this course (and in your own work), you will be writing lots of programs. Generally the first draft is not the final draft, be it a research paper or a computer script. We want a way to track our changes over time.
Perhaps this is to make sure we have a record of what we&amp;rsquo;ve already done that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, so we can avoid doing it again. Or maybe we want to share our code with collaborators who are working on a project with us.</description></item><item><title>Install Git</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git/</guid><description>This page provides instructions to install Git for Windows, Mac OX, and Linux.
Git Installation: Windows Install Git for Windows, also known as msysgit or &amp;ldquo;Git Bash&amp;rdquo;, to get Git in addition to some other useful tools, such as the Bash shell. Yes, all those names are totally confusing, but you might encounter them elsewhere and I want you to be well-informed.
This method of installing Git for Windows leaves the Git executable in a conventional location, which will help you and other programs, e.</description></item><item><title>Git clients</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-clients/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-clients/</guid><description>You can use Git for version control through the command line or through a Git client. For the first option, see What is the Shell?. Here we are going to focus on Git clients.
Learning how and why to use Git can be rough. Therefore, using a client, rather than the command line, is usually helpful when getting started. Most clients help you interface with Git and GitHub through a user-friendly Graphical User Interface (GUI), but they still perform the same underlying Git commands that you would perform through the command line.</description></item><item><title>Configure Git</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-configure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-configure/</guid><description>note To ensure minimal challenges using Git during the class, we want to configure Git now with some default settings. You only have to do this once per machine.
Identify yourself In order to track changes and attribute them to the correct user, we need to tell Git your name and email address. Run the following commands from the R console:
usethis::use_git_config(user.name = &amp;#34;Jean Clipperton&amp;#34;, user.email = &amp;#34;email@gmail.com&amp;#34;) Replace Jean Clipperton and email@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Using Git within RStudio</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</guid><description>Complete these steps after you have Installed Git (only if you are working with R Studio locally) and Configured Git (for both local and R Workbench option) to verify that everything works as expected. If you are not sure, begin by reading Start here: Software Options.
Step 0: Make sure RStudio can find Git If everything is installed correctly&amp;hellip; File &amp;gt; New Project. If you see a Version Control options, that&amp;rsquo;s good.</description></item></channel></rss>