<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to CFSS! on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to CFSS! on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A1: Practice editing .Rmd and generating .md</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/edit-readme/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 13:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/edit-readme/</guid><description>Overview The goal is to test your software installation, your GitHub setup, and the homework submission process, as well as demonstrate basic competency in Markdown and R Markdown.
Accessing your A1 repository Go to this link to accept and create your private a1 repository on GitHub. Once you do so, your repository will be built in a few seconds. It follows the naming convention a1-&amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt; Once the your repository has been created, click on the link you see, which will take you to your repository.</description></item><item><title>A2: Exploring and visualizing data</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/explore-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/explore-data/</guid><description>Transform and explore a cleaned dataset on gun deaths in the United States.</description></item><item><title>A3: Wrangling and visualizing data</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/wrangle-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 13:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/wrangle-data/</guid><description>Wrangle and explore messy datasets in practical research environments.</description></item><item><title>A4: Programming in R</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/programming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 13:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/programming/</guid><description>Practice programming techniques in R.</description></item><item><title>A5: Debugging and practice working with functions</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/debugging-rmarkdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/debugging-rmarkdown/</guid><description>Resolve code errors and practice writing and using functions with social science data.</description></item><item><title>A6: Collecting and analyzing data from the web</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/webdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/webdata/</guid><description>Collect data from the web and analyze it.</description></item><item><title>Final: Generating reproducible social science research</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/reproducible-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/reproducible-research/</guid><description>Synthesize everything we have learned thus far.</description></item><item><title>A7: Analyzing textual data</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/assignments/text-analysis/</guid><description>Collect text data and analyze it.</description></item><item><title>General Questions &amp; Info</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/about-the-course/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/about-the-course/</guid><description>General description This course is open to any graduate (or advanced undergraduate) at the University of Chicago. We draw from a wide range of departments such as Information Science, Sociology, Psychology, Political Science, etc. Typically these students are looking to learn basic computational and analytic skills they can apply to master’s projects or dissertation research.
If you have never programmed before or don’t know what the shell is, prepare for a different way of approaching problems.</description></item><item><title>What is Git?</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/what-is-git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/what-is-git/</guid><description>Why Git? In this course (and in your own work), you will be writing lots of programs. Generally the first draft is not the final draft, be it a research paper or a computer script. We want a way to track our changes over time.
Perhaps this is to make sure we have a record of what we&amp;rsquo;ve already done that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, so we can avoid doing it again. Or maybe we want to share our code with collaborators who are working on a project with us.</description></item><item><title>Homework Rubric</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/homework-evaluations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/homework-evaluations/</guid><description>Evaluation philosophy The university requires that I assign each student a letter grade at the end of the quarter. However I find that numeric scores on assignments tend to cause students grading anxiety if they do not achieve a perfect 100%. Nor does the numeric score convey specific feedback as to what the student has done well on an assignment, combined with feedback on areas for improvement.
As such, I do not assign numeric scores in this class.</description></item><item><title>Install Git</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git/</guid><description>This page provides instructions to install Git for Windows, Mac OX, and Linux.
Git Installation: Windows Install Git for Windows, also known as msysgit or &amp;ldquo;Git Bash&amp;rdquo;, to get Git in addition to some other useful tools, such as the Bash shell. Yes, all those names are totally confusing, but you might encounter them elsewhere and I want you to be well-informed.
This method of installing Git for Windows leaves the Git executable in a conventional location, which will help you and other programs, e.</description></item><item><title>Why R?</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/what-is-r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/what-is-r/</guid><description>Open-source R is open-source software, which means using it is completely free. Second, open-source software is developed collaboratively, meaning the source code is open to public inspection, modification, and improvement.
Popular R is widely used in the physical and social sciences, as well as in government, non-profits, and the private sector.
Many developers and social scientists write programs in R. As a result, there is also a large support community available to help troubleshoot problematic code.</description></item><item><title>Git clients</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-clients/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-clients/</guid><description>You can use Git for version control through the command line or through a Git client. For the first option, see What is the Shell?. Here we are going to focus on Git clients.
Learning how and why to use Git can be rough. Therefore, using a client, rather than the command line, is usually helpful when getting started. Most clients help you interface with Git and GitHub through a user-friendly Graphical User Interface (GUI), but they still perform the same underlying Git commands that you would perform through the command line.</description></item><item><title>Setup R</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/r/</guid><description>R R is an open-source programming language based on the S from the 1970s. It is very popular in the physical and social sciences due to it&amp;rsquo;s cost (free) and versatility. Thousands of expansion libraries have been published which extend the tasks R can perform, and users can write their own custom functions and/or libraries to perform specific operations.
Installing R Download the latest binary distribution for your operating system (e.</description></item><item><title>Configure Git</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-configure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-configure/</guid><description>note To ensure minimal challenges using Git during the class, we want to configure Git now with some default settings. You only have to do this once per machine.
Identify yourself In order to track changes and attribute them to the correct user, we need to tell Git your name and email address. Run the following commands from the R console:
usethis::use_git_config(user.name = &amp;#34;Jean Clipperton&amp;#34;, user.email = &amp;#34;email@gmail.com&amp;#34;) Replace Jean Clipperton and email@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Accessing RStudio Workbench</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/r-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/r/r-server/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with a few definitions:
R R is an open-source programming language based on the S from the 1970s. It is very popular in the physical and social sciences due to it&amp;rsquo;s cost (free) and versatility. Thousands of expansion libraries have been published which extend the tasks R can perform, and users can write their own custom functions and/or libraries to perform specific operations.
RStudio The base R distribution is not the best for developing and writing programs.</description></item><item><title>How to ask for help</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/asking-questions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/faq/asking-questions/</guid><description>Asking questions is an important part of this class. Remember the 15 minute rule: Once you’ve spent 15 minutes attempting to troubleshoot a problem, ask for help.
Questions should be posted to Ed Discussion in the appropriate category (general v discussion). Here are some tips you should always follow when posting questions.
Introduce the problem with an informative title Bad title: “I need help!” Good title: “Getting a ‘file not found error’ when importing scotus.</description></item><item><title>Using Git within RStudio</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</guid><description>Complete these steps after you have Installed Git (only if you are working with R Studio locally) and Configured Git (for both local and R Workbench option) to verify that everything works as expected. If you are not sure, begin by reading Start here: Software Options.
Step 0: Make sure RStudio can find Git If everything is installed correctly&amp;hellip; File &amp;gt; New Project. If you see a Version Control options, that&amp;rsquo;s good.</description></item><item><title>Juneteenth (observed)</title><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/juneteenth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/juneteenth/</guid><description>No class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/application-program-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/application-program-interface/</guid><description>Overview Identify multiple methods for obtaining data from the internet Define web-scraping Define Application Program Interface (API) Explain APIs authentication keys and demonstrate secure methods for storing these keys Interact with APIs Define JSON data structure and how to convert them to data frames Before class Chapter 1 and 4 in Web Scraping with R Setup: Go to the geonames site and register an account Click here to enable the free web service Go to the OMDb website and click on the “API Key” tab to generate your API key Several packages are needed for this week’s lectures (all installed on R workbench).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/build-better-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/build-better-workflow/</guid><description>Overview Identify the importance of preprocessing data sets Introduce the recipes package for preprocessing data Utilize usemodels to automatically construct code templates for common model types Construct workflows for machine learning Before class Read Preprocess your data Read Tune model parameters This is not a math/stats class. In class we will briefly summarize how these methods work and spend the bulk of our time on estimating and interpreting these models. That said, you should have some understanding of the mathematical underpinnings of statistical learning methods prior to implementing them yourselves.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/classification-topic-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/classification-topic-models/</guid><description>Overview Introduce supervised and unsupervised text classification Define sentiment analysis and demonstrate its use (Chapter 2) Define topic modeling with Latent Dirichlet allocation and demonstrate its use (Chapter 6) Before class Read Chapter 2 and Chapter 6 in Tidy Text Mining with R Read Probabilistic Topic Models by Blei, David (2012) Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s in-class materials: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;CFSS-MACSS/text-analysis-fundamentals-and-sentiment-analysis-and-tm&amp;quot;) Additional resources See additional resources for the previous lecture on text analysis and regular expressions Original Topic Modeling (LDA) article by Blei, David M.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-communication/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-structures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-structures/</guid><description>Overview Recognize and manipulate R Data Structures (especially vectors and lists) Review control structures and functions Before class Read Chapter 20 “Vectors” in R for Data Science Optional: Chapter 14 “Strings” in R for Data Science Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s in-class exercises: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;CFSS-MACSS/data-structures&amp;quot;) What you need to do after class Work on Homework 5</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-transformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/data-transformation/</guid><description>Overview Identify programming as a form of problem solving Practice decomposing a goal into a set of discrete, computational tasks Identify the basic verbs for a language of data manipulation Familiarize with Pipes Practice transforming data Before class Required: read Chapter 5 “Data Transformation” and Chapter 18 “Pipes” from R for Data Science Class materials Computer programming as a form of problem solving dplyr in brief Practice transforming college education data Additional resources Cheat sheet Data Wrangling with dplyr and tidyr What you need to do after class Start Homework 2 Review this week’s readings and notes</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/debugging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/debugging/</guid><description>Overview Define a bug Review best practices for reading, writing, and styling code Distinguish between errors, warnings, and messages Identify and practice methods for error handling and recovery Before class Read “Debugging R code” in What They Forgot to Teach You About R Skim The tidyverse style guide Read How to read an R help page Review 21.6 Dealing with failure in R for Data Science Class materials No in-class materials (today we complete in-class materials for “Data Structures” lecture) Review the assigned readings for further insights and practice Additional Resources Bugs and styling code Debugging and condition handling Naming things - by Jenny Bryan.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/distributed-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/distributed-learning/</guid><description>Overview Discuss the need for distributed computing Illustrate the split-apply-combine analytical pattern Define parallel processing Define SQL Demonstrate how to access local and remote SQL databases Introduce Hadoop and Spark as distributed computing platforms Introduce the sparklyr package Demonstrate how to use sparklyr for machine learning using the Titanic data set Before class Install sparklyr and H2O on your local computer. Run the code below to install all necessary packages and set the correct options.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/exploratory-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/exploratory-data-analysis/</guid><description>Overview Define Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) and types of pattern exploration Demonstrate types of graphs useful for EDA and precautions when interpreting them Define factors Practice exploring data Before class Read Chapter 7 “Exploratory Data Analysis” and Chapter 15 “Factors” from R for Data Science Class materials Exploratory data analysis Practice exploring college education data Additional resources Antony Unwin Graphical Data Analysis with R. It covers a range of graphical methods for data exploration and analysis; draws on packages beyond ggplot2 for statistical graphics.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/extended-git-workflows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/extended-git-workflows/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials Additional resources What you need to do after class Complete the homework assignment</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/fall-break/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/fall-break/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/git-and-github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/git-and-github/</guid><description>Overview Familiarize with R syntax, data types, and data structures Distinguish between R scripts (.R), Markdown documents (.md), and R Markdown documents (.Rmd) Identify the major components of R Markdown Create repositories Make commits and synchronize repositories from RStudio Before class Read chapter 4 “Workflow Basics” in R for Data Science Read Data Carpentry Introduction to R Read chapter 27 “R Markdown” in R for Data Science Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s lecture and exercises: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;CFSS-MACSS/intro-r&amp;quot;)[1] Using Git within R Studio Additional resources Markdown and R Markdown by Pat Bartlein R Markdown from R Studio official documentation Practice your R skills with DataCamp free Introduction to R course What you need to do after class If you haven’t yet: Install and setup software Start Homework 1 [1] If you are using R from your local machine: first install the library by typing in your console install.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/grammar-of-graphics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/grammar-of-graphics/</guid><description>Overview Identify the importance of graphics in communicating information Define the layered grammar of graphics Demonstrate how to use layered grammar of graphics Practice generating layered graphics using ggplot2 Before class Required: read chapter 3 from R for Data Science. You need to read this chapter and complete some of the exercises before coming to class. Exercise solutions can be found here. Optional: read Hadley Wickham A Layered Grammar of Graphics – the “pre-print” version of the article can be downloaded for free.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/hyperparameter-tuning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/hyperparameter-tuning/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials note note Additional readings What you need to do after class Complete the machine learning homework</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/independence-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/independence-day/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/intro/</guid><description>Overview Introduction to the course Identify major course objectives Identify course logistics and expectations Familiarize with basic principles of programming and reproducible workflow Software setup instructions Before class Read the “Welcome” page and chapter 1 “Introduction” in R for Data Science. (Note that there is a new draft we’ll be moving to soon: Second Edition of R for Data Science) Class materials Introduction to computing for the social sciences Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/labor-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/labor-day/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/memorial-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/memorial-day/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/mlk-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/mlk-day/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/no-class-misc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/no-class-misc/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/pipes-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/pipes-functions/</guid><description>Overview Review control structures Define functions and their purpose Analyze a user-written function and explain how it works Practice writing functions Before class Read Chapter 17 “Introduction” and chapter 19 “Functions” in R for Data Science Review Chapter 21 “Iteration” in R for Data Science Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s in-class exercises: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;css-materials/functions&amp;quot;) What you need to do after class Homework assignments Review today’s lecture materials, and prepare for next class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/r-markdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/r-markdown/</guid><description>Overview Review the importance of reproducibility in scientific research Identify the major components of .Rmd Define knitr chunks Implement chunk options to customize output Practice different R Markdown formats Before class Read chapters 27 “R Markdown”, 28 “Graphics for communication”, and 29 “R Markdown formats” in R for Data Science Additional resources Consult these resources for further information about R Markdown, it is likely they will provide the answer to what you need: * R Markdown the definitive Guide * R Markdown cheat sheet * Markdown and R Markdown by Pat Bartlein * R Markdown from R Studio official documentation * Info on the lubridate package: Chapter 16 of R for Data Science</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/relational-data-factors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/relational-data-factors/</guid><description>Overview Introduce relational data Demonstrate how tables can be linked to one another Demonstrate methods in dplyr for linking and merging related tables Practice joining tables Review factors Before class Read Chapter 13 “Relational Data” in R for Data Science. Do not complete exercises 13.4.6.2-3 – we will be completing these as in-class exercises Review Chapter 15 “Factors” in R for Data Science Class materials Practice using relational data What you need to do after class Keep working on homework 3 Review lectures and readings</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reprex-git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reprex-git/</guid><description>Overview Review Git/GitHub basic workflow using the R GUI Learn how to use basic Git/GitHub workflow through the command line Good practices Common problems and how to solve them Before class Chapter 1 Why Git? Why GitHub? in “Happy Git and GitHub for the useR” Read “Excuse me, do you have a moment to talk about version control?” Skim chapters 15, 16, and 17 included in the section Early GitHub Wins in “Happy Git and GitHub for the useR” Skim chapters 20 to 23 in the section Git fundamentals in “Happy Git and GitHub for the useR” We will be using R Workbench for the lecture and the in-class exercises.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reproducible-documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reproducible-documents/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reproducible-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/reproducible-workflow/</guid><description>Overview Review the importance of reproducibility in scientific research Define a project-oriented workflow Practice implementing it in R Identify R startup procedures Before class Read chapters 1, 2, 3, 7 in What They Forgot to Teach You About R Class materials In-class practice instructions are included in the slides for today Additional resources Book What They Forgot to Teach You About R Article on Project-oriented workflow After class Complete Hw04</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/shiny-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/shiny-server/</guid><description>Overview Review Shiny apps Define reactivity Build the server component of a Shiny app Before class Class materials Tutorial from class
Git repo for dating age rule app
Chicago wage employees sample app
What you need to do after class Finish Shiny homework assignment</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/shiny-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/shiny-ui/</guid><description>Overview Introduce Shiny apps Demonstrate each element of a Shiny app Distinguish UI from server components Build the UI component of a Shiny app Before class Class materials Tutorial from class
shiny-demo - fork and clone this repo to follow along with the in-class exercise
Git repo for dating age rule app
Chicago wage employees sample app
What you need to do after class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/spatial-viz-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/spatial-viz-i/</guid><description>Overview Introduce the major components of a geospatial visualization Identify how to draw raster maps using ggmaps and get_map() Practice generating raster maps Demonstrate geofacet and facet_geo() Before class Read Introduction to geospatial visualization Read Drawing raster maps with ggmap Class materials Practice drawing raster maps
Mapping data in The Truthful Art by Alberto Cairo - excellent chapter on designing data maps with lots of examples. Though really the entire book is useful if you do a lot of work with data visualizations of any type.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/spatial-viz-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/spatial-viz-ii/</guid><description>Overview Define shapefiles and import spatial data using the sf package Draw maps using ggplot2 and geom_sf() Change coordinate systems Generate appropriate color palettes to visualize additional dimensions of data Before class Read Importing shapefiles using sf Read Drawing vector maps with ggplot2 and sf Class materials Selecting optimal color palettes
Practice drawing vector maps
Mapping data in The Truthful Art by Alberto Cairo - excellent chapter on designing data maps with lots of examples.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/stat-learn-classification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/stat-learn-classification/</guid><description>Overview Define a decision tree Demonstrate how to estimate a decision tree Define and estimate a random forest Introduce the caret package for statistical learning in R Define resampling method Compare and contrast the validation set approach with leave-one-out and k-fold cross-validation Demonstrate how to conduct cross-validation using rsample Before class This is not a math/stats class. In class we will briefly summarize how these methods work and spend the bulk of our time on estimating and interpreting these models.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/stat-learn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/stat-learn/</guid><description>Overview Review the major goals of machine learning Introduce the tidymodels and parsnip packages for estimating regression models Define resampling methods for evaluating model performance Demonstrate how to conduct cross-validation using rsample Before class Read Statistical learning: the basics Read Build a model Read Evaluate your model with resampling This is not a math/stats class. In class we will briefly summarize how these methods work and spend the bulk of our time on estimating and interpreting these models.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/text-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/text-data/</guid><description>Overview Introduce regular expressions Identify the basic workflow for conducting text analysis Define the tidy text formats (Chapter 1) Word frequencies and tf-idf (Chapter 1 and 3) Before class For this and the following lecture we use the book Tidy Text Mining with R. Before this class: read Chapter 1, 3, and 4. Before next class: read chapters 2 and 6
Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s in-class materials: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;CFSS-MACSS/text-analysis-fundamentals&amp;quot;) Additional resources Basic text analysis: * The three case studies included in the book “Text Mining with R” (see assigned readings) provide in-depth examples on how to preform text analysis from A-Z.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/thanksgiving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/thanksgiving/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/tidy-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/tidy-data/</guid><description>Overview Import data in R Define tidy data and its characteristics Practice tidying data Before class Required: read Chapter 11 “Data Import” and Chapter 12 “Tidy data” from R for Data Science Optional: read Chapter 10 “Tibbles” from R for Data Science Class materials Tidy data Practice tidying data Additional resources Lohr. 2014. For Big-Data Scientists, “Janitor Work” Is Key Hurdle to Insights. New York Times Data Carpentry a response to the NYTimes article Pivoting in tidyr What you need to do after class Complete Homework 2 Review today’s lecture materials, and prepare for next class Start Homework 3</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/tidyeval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/tidyeval/</guid><description>Overview Before class Class materials What you need to do after class Complete the programming homework</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/vectors-iteration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/vectors-iteration/</guid><description>Overview Introduce if-else statements Introduce iterative operations Practice writing iterative operations using loops, map() functions, and dplyr::across() Before class Read Chapter 13 “Control Structures” in R programming for Data Science Read Chapter 21 “Iteration” in R for Data Science Class materials Run the code below in your console to download today’s in-class exercises: usethis::use_course(&amp;quot;css-materials/control-structures&amp;quot;) What you need to do after class Complete/Start Homework assignments Review today’s lecture materials, and prepare for next class</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/web-scraping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/web-scraping/</guid><description>Overview Define HTML and CSS selectors Introduce the rvest package Demonstrate how to extract information from HTML pages Practice scraping data Before class Chapter 1 and 4 in Web Scraping with R Several packages are needed for this week’s lectures (all installed on R workbench). If you are using R from your laptop (VS. R Workbench), I’d suggest following the lectures using R Workbench and installing the packages after class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/work-with-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfssmacss.netlify.app/schedule/work-with-models/</guid><description>Overview Combine multiple ggplot() objects using patchwork Fit multiple regression lines as separate layers in ggplot() Generate legends using single-value variables Identify principles for visualizing statistical model estimates Generate predicted values from models for graphing Plot marginal effects using margins Before class Read Work with Models in Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction
Install the following packages:
install.packages(c(&amp;quot;socviz&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;margins&amp;quot;)) remotes::install_github(&amp;quot;thomasp85/patchwork&amp;quot;) Class materials Working with statistical models What you need to do after class Complete the statistical learning homework</description></item></channel></rss>