<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/setup/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Git?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/what-is-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/what-is-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-git&#34;&gt;Why Git?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course (and in your own work), you will be writing lots of&#xA;programs. Generally the first draft is not the final draft, be it a&#xA;research paper or a computer script. We want a way to track our changes&#xA;over time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is to make sure we have a record of what we’ve already done&#xA;that doesn’t work, so we can avoid doing it again. Or maybe we want to&#xA;share our code with collaborators who are working on a project with us.&#xA;How can we do this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Git</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page provides instructions to install Git for Windows, Mac OX, and&#xA;Linux.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;git-installation-windows&#34;&gt;Git Installation: Windows&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-for-windows.github.io/&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;, also&#xA;known as &lt;code&gt;msysgit&lt;/code&gt; or “Git Bash”, to get Git in addition to some other&#xA;useful tools, such as the Bash shell. Yes, all those names are totally&#xA;confusing, but you might encounter them elsewhere and I want you to be&#xA;well-informed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This method of installing Git for Windows leaves the Git executable in a&#xA;conventional location, which will help you and other programs,&#xA;e.g. RStudio, find it and use it. This also supports a transition to&#xA;more expert use, because the “Git Bash” shell will be useful as you&#xA;venture outside of R/RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git clients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-clients/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can use Git for version control through the command line or through&#xA;a Git client. For the first option, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/setup/shell/&#34;&gt;What is the&#xA;Shell?&lt;/a&gt;. Here we are going to focus on Git clients.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learning how and why to use Git can be rough. Therefore, using a client,&#xA;rather than the command line, is usually helpful when getting started.&#xA;Most clients help you interface with Git and GitHub through a&#xA;user-friendly Graphical User Interface (GUI), but they still perform the&#xA;same underlying Git commands that you would perform through the command&#xA;line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Git</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-configure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-configure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;note&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To ensure minimal challenges using Git during the class, we want to&#xA;configure Git now with some default settings. &lt;strong&gt;You only have to do this&#xA;once per machine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;identify-yourself&#34;&gt;Identify yourself&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to track changes and attribute them to the correct user, we&#xA;need to tell Git your name and email address. Run the following commands&#xA;from the R console:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;usethis::use_git_config(user.name = &amp;quot;Sabrina Nardin&amp;quot;, user.email = &amp;quot;email@gmail.com&amp;quot;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;Sabrina Nardin&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;email@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; with your name and email&#xA;address. Your name could be your GitHub username, or your actual first&#xA;and last name. &lt;strong&gt;Your email address must be the email address associated&#xA;with your GitHub account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Git within RStudio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/git/git-with-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complete these steps after you have Installed Git (only if you are&#xA;working with R Studio locally) and Configured Git (for both local and R&#xA;Workbench option) to verify that everything works as expected. If you&#xA;are not sure, begin by reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/setup/&#34;&gt;Start here: Software&#xA;Options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-0-make-sure-rstudio-can-find-git&#34;&gt;Step 0: Make sure RStudio can find Git&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;if-everything-is-installed-correctly&#34;&gt;If everything is installed correctly…&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;File &amp;gt; New Project&lt;/em&gt;. If you see a Version Control options, that’s&#xA;good. Do not select it. Instead, select &lt;em&gt;New Directory &amp;gt; New&#xA;Project&lt;/em&gt;. Do you see a check box “Create a git repository”? If yes,&#xA;that’s good. Check it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Give this test project a name and click “Create Project”. Do you see a&#xA;“Git” tab in the upper right pane, the same one that has “Environment”&#xA;and “History”? If yes, good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If this worked, you can delete the project. You’ve set everything up&#xA;correctly (if you are working on R Workbench this should automatically&#xA;work). To delete the project, go to the “Files” tab (bottom right&#xA;corner), select the project folder and click “Delete”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
