<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R/RStudio on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R/RStudio on CFSS: Computing for the Social Sciences</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/setup/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why R?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/what-is-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/what-is-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source&#34;&gt;Open-source&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R is open-source software, which means using it is &lt;strong&gt;completely free&lt;/strong&gt;. Second, open-source software is developed &lt;strong&gt;collaboratively&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning the source code is open to public inspection, modification, and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;popular&#34;&gt;Popular&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R is widely used in the physical and social sciences, &lt;a href=&#34;http://spectrum.ieee.org/static/interactive-the-top-programming-languages-2016&#34;&gt;as well as in government, non-profits, and the private sector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many developers and social scientists write programs in R. As a result, there is also a large support community available to help troubleshoot problematic code. As seen in the Redmonk programming language rankings (which compare languages&amp;rsquo; appearances on Github [usage] and StackOverflow [support]), R appears near the top of both rankings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source programming language based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;S&lt;/a&gt; from the 1970s. It is very popular in the physical and social sciences due to it&amp;rsquo;s cost (free) and versatility. Thousands of expansion libraries have been published which extend the tasks R can perform, and users can write their own custom functions and/or libraries to perform specific operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-r&#34;&gt;Installing R&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download the latest binary distribution for your operating system (e.g. Windows, Mac OS X, or Linux) from &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;CRAN&lt;/a&gt;, a network of servers around the world which store identical copies of the R binaries, source code, and thousands of additional libraries. The binary version has been pre-compiled and is the easiest to install. Windows users should make sure to select the binary for the &lt;em&gt;base distribution&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run the installation from the file you just downloaded (&lt;code&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.pkg&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open R. You should see a screen similar to this:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;r_console.png&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the default R console. You can use this as your development environment where you write and execute code. However the default R console is very minimalistic and not much more useful than a text editor. This is why we will use RStudio for programming in R. However to demonstrate that your R installation works, type &lt;code&gt;5 + 2&lt;/code&gt; in the console and press enter. You should see the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing RStudio Workbench</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/r-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/setup/r/r-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with a few definitions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source programming language based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;S&lt;/a&gt; from the 1970s. It is very popular in the physical and social sciences due to it&amp;rsquo;s cost (free) and versatility. Thousands of expansion libraries have been published which extend the tasks R can perform, and users can write their own custom functions and/or libraries to perform specific operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rstudio&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The base R distribution is not the best for developing and writing programs. Instead, we want an integrated development environment (IDE) which will allow us to write and execute code, debug programs, and automate certain tasks. In this course we will use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/RStudio/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps the most popular IDE available for R. Like R, it is open-source, expandable, and provides many useful tools and enhancements over the base R environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
